### **Abhinav CHADHA**

6 Mavoncliff Drive Age: 34

Tattenhoe Nationality: French

MK4 3DP, Milton Keynes Web: <a href="https://about.me/abhinavchadha">https://about.me/abhinavchadha</a>

Cell: +44 7404 780325 Email: abhinavdchadha@gmail.com

Software engineer turned Product Manager with 10+ years of experience working for enterprise and startups. I have worked closely with C level executives in early stage startups to define the vision and also implement strategy around product, people and company culture. In my current role, I work with a very high impact global KPMG leadership team on discovering, grooming and developing new product lines for KPMG UK.

I pride myself with crisp and concise communication, excellent technical knowledge about cloud and cloud applications along with their development, design and delivery. Whilst working on turnkey projects, I have stellar experience leading local and remote teams. Teamwork, solid communication and motivating peers to achieve their goals using OKR methodology form the basis of my team management strategy.

#### Product Manager @ KPMG, London, United Kingdom (May 2022 – Present)

- Lead the product proposition for an ESG Data-aaS application enabling KPMG to compete with data vendors on a global scale.
- Lead the product proposition for a team working with the Ministry of Defence to deliver a high impact asset management toolset bringing in savings and optimisation of hundreds of thousands of Pounds for the MoD.
- Manage a team working on a patient analytics product for the NHS bringing high efficiency and throughput for the hospitals.
- Gather requirements from the business stakeholders considering client usage and internal use and thereby build on specifications for the Analytics features by defining the front-end and back-end using FRD.
- Drive the design and discovery sprint with internal and external stakeholders.
- Manage a team of 30+ engineers in India, UK and Poland.
- Identify and mitigate financial, technological and proposition risk.
- Designing value proposition and revenue model for the sponsors and new customers to continue with the financial inflow.
- Manage SteerCo and ExCo members, technology partners and data vendors.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Skills</u>: Stakeholder management, Product Discovery, Product Design, Design Thinking, Team Management, PMO, Corporate Finance, Financial modelling, GTM Strategy, User Interviewing, Google Looker, Tableau, MS Office, Figma, Miro, Trello, Asana, Jira, Confluence.

#### Lead QA Engineer @ KPMG, London, United Kingdom (Sep. 2021 – May 2022)

 Lead QA Engineer responsible for the implementation of automated tests and testing best practices in the feature team, managing stakeholders whilst liaising with PMO for seamless delivery of features.

<u>Skills</u>: Javascript, Typescript, Cypress, Python3, Selenium, Azure, Shell, Docker, K8s, PMO, Stakeholder Management.

#### **Delivery Consultant** @ **ECS**, London, United Kingdom (Dec. 2019 – Aug. 2021)

- Senior Test Automation Consultant for ECS' clients, I evaluated feasibility, risk, impact and defined roadmap for IT consulting activities and implementing the best solution possible.
- Worked for clients like Barclays Bank, Asian Logic, Dafabet and Nationwide Building Society (NBS).

<u>Skills</u>: Python3, Javascript, Typescript, Cypress, Selenium, AWS, Shell, Docker, K8s, Test Reporting, Test Management, Atlassian, Project Management, Product Management, Technical Writing, Terraform, Ansible, Gitlab CI.

#### Test Engineering and Release Manager @ ContentSquare, London, United Kingdom - Paris, France (Jan. 2018 – Nov. 2019)

Lead the Test Engineering team of six engineers who work on different feature teams and liaison with remote teams in Tel Aviv and Kiev.

Skills: Python3, Javascript, Selenium, Cypress, NodeJS, Appium, WebDriverIO, Terraform, AWS, Docker, REST-ful WS, Jenkins, Shell, Kafka, PG-SQL, MySQL, Team Management, Creation of KPI based roadmap, OKR, Mentoring, Agile.

#### QA Engineer @ Qonto, Paris, France (Jun. 2017 – Jan. 2018)

Development, management and maintenance of a Slackbot using errbot framework and Python3 to facilitate deployment of production ready code.

Skills: Ruby, Python3, SlackAPI, Github API, Selenium, Docker, AWS, EmberJS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, REST-ful WS, Shell, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ.

#### QA Manager @ Tinyclues, Paris, France (Aug. 2015 – Jun. 2017)

Development and maintenance of the in-house automated test framework built on Python2 and managing the service on production liaising with the Product Management team to follow the roadmaps.

Skills: ChatOps, Python, GoLang, Selenium, Docker, AWS, SaltStack, Ansible,

#### **PROFESSIONAL** EXPERIENCE

Terraform, StackStorm, Mistral, OpenStack, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, REST-ful WS, Shell, GIT, BDD, TDD.

#### Quality Analyst @ SmartFocus, Paris, France (Jun. 2013 – Jul. 2015)

- Development of in-house test automation framework using Python2.
- Development of user stories in an AGILE environment, working alongside the Scrum Masters and the Business Analysts.

Skills: Python, Selenium, Oracle, PostGRE-SQL, Redis, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, NodeJS, REST-ful WS, Shell, JMS, Build Management, Incident Management.

#### Test Automation Developer (Intern) @ Orange Labs Products and Services (OLPS), Rennes, France (Jul. 2012 – Jan. 2013)

Study and development of Deep Packet Inspectors (DPI) used for network diagnostics and testing based purely on Python for diagnostics and performance tests.

Skills: Python, TCP/IP, Embedded Systems, Shell, IPTABLES, Network Diagnostics.

**ISTQB Certified Tester** (Foundation Level: May 2014)

<u>CERTIFICATIONS</u> <u>AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner</u> (April 2020)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (November 2020)



### **EDUCATION**

Institut Supérieur d'Electronique de Paris (ISEP), Paris, France (Oct. 2011 -Jan. 2013) - Master of Science (MSc)

University of Pune, Pune, India (Aug. 2006 – Aug. 2011) - Bachelor of **Engineering (BE)** 

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Founding member for a community led incubator funded partly by the Indian Embassy in Paris' Science and Technology fund to promote Indian entrepreneurs to start up in France (2017-18).
- French Government Scholarship Holder recipient of the Orange-MAEE (Ministère des Affaires Etrangères et Européennes) joint scholarship for the year 2011-12.
- Fellow of the Consultancy Development Center, Ministry of Science and Technology, HRD, Government of India in February 2010 for consulting a live project.

#### **LANGUAGES**

French (Fluent), English (Bilingual), Hindi (Mother Tongue)

**HOBBIES** 

Photography, Biking, Swimming, Badminton, Reading.